# PRANAY SINGH PARIHAR

**DEVOPS ENGINEER** 

#### **Contact Info**

7568591982 pranaysparihar@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

I am an experienced DevOps Engineer, with experience working on major cloud providers like AWS, Azure and GCP withholding the certifications as well and with expertise on CI/CD tools like Terraform and Ansible along with git and Azure DevOps.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

- DevOps Engineer NCR Corporation Dec 2021 - present
- Worked on groovy script to invoke functions on remote server for Jenkins pipeline.
- Experience in designing a Terraform and deploying it in cloud deployment manager to spin up resources like cloud virtual networks, Compute Engines in public and private subnets along with AutoScaler in Google Cloud Platform.
- Set up a GCP Firewall rules in order to allow or deny traffic to and from the VM's instances based on specified configuration and used GCP cloud CDN (content delivery network) to deliver content from GCP cache locations drastically improving user experience and latency.
- Experience in providing highly available and fault tolerant applications utilizing orchestration technologies like Kubernetes and Apache Mesos on Google Cloud Platform.
- Experience in Blue/green deployment strategy by creating new applications which are identical to the existing production environment using CloudFormation templates & Route53 weighted record sets to redirect traffic from the old environment to the pristine environment via DNS.
- DevOps Engineer IbexLabs Nov2021 - Dec2021
- Working on Ansible scripts to install Cloudwatch agent on EC2 instances and monitor metrics like Volumeusage, memoryusage and CPUusage.
- Setting up multiple environment variables input on GitHub to deploy images to ECR.

DevOps Engineer TwimBit Sept2021 - Oct2021

- Setup CloudFront along with Application Load Balancers for ECS.
- Setup Task definitions for a Caddy server and static website.
- Write Nginx configuration to reverse proxy traffic within the cluster and to serve SSL certificate on the go with the help of OpenResty Framework.
- Managing the entire infrastructure using terraform.
   Setup Lambda function for database failover and automate the process using step functions.
- Setup A records and CNAME in Route 53.
- DevOps Engineer
  Neudesic
  March2021 Aug2021
- Created a Windows server image using Hashicorp
   Packer
- Deploys the Packer image on Azure Virtual Machine Scale Set using Terraform.
- Manages a GKE cluster using Terraform.
- Sets up Load Balancer for the Kubernetes cluster.
- DevOps Intern
   Tivona Global
   Oct2020 Feb2021
- Continuous deployment automation using bash scripting.
- Automated AWS cloud deployment using Terraform from scratch.
- Implemented terraform functions on Terraform cloud.
- Implemented sentinel policies on Terraform cloud.
- Using dynamic blocks to dynamically create multiple resources of block within a resource from a complex value such as a list of map.
- Create IAM policies for users and attach them to an IAM group.
- Lambda function to attach the IAM policy to an IAM user and save the CloudTrail logs for IAM user in DynamoDB, using Boto.

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

#### SOFTWARE

Amazon Web Services Terraform Jira

Azure Bash Confluence

Git Azure DevOps Slack
VS Code

Python Docker

IAM AWS Lambda
Google Cloud Platform DynamoDB

#### **EDUCATION HISTORY**

**Bachelor Of Technology** VIT University, Chennai 2017 - 2021

- Under Graduated in Electrical and Electronics Engineering.
- Studied electrical machines, control systems, and signals and systems.

#### **ACHIEVMENTS**

#### **Recognized as a Terraform Subject Matter Expert:**

- Recognized as Terraform Subject Matter Expert
- Recognized by Neudesic as a Subject Matter expert for my work with Microsoft
- · Helped with internal projects of Neudesic

#### **Tier-1 Udemy Course**

- Recognized as a Terraform Udemy Instructor.
- Authored practice questions for the Terraform associate exam.
- Regarded as the second-largest question bank for practice available online.
- My course got recognized as a tier-1 course on the Udemy platform

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Amazon Web Services:	Microsoft:	Terraform:
<ul> <li>AWS Cloud Practitioner</li> </ul>	• AZ-900	<ul> <li>Terraform Certified Cloud</li> </ul>
		Associate

Aviatrix:

## • Istio and IBM Cloud

Kubernetes Service

IBM:

Engineer

• Aviatrix Certified • Digital Cloud Leader

**Google Cloud Platform:**